Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: European Skyways, 1926; 14 (Box 1542)
    - Verso: Germany; Nachahmung wird strafrechtlich verfolgt. Alleiniges Urheberrecht bei Luftverkehr Strahle, Schorndorf (Wurtt,), 3-verso
    - Germany; Nachahmung wird strafrechtlich verfolgt. Alleiniges Urheberrecht bei Luftverkehr Strahle, Schorndorf (Wurtt,), 4
    - Verso: Germany; Nachahmung wird strafrechtlich verfolgt. Alleiniges Urheberrecht bei Luftverkehr Strahle, Schorndorf (Wurtt,), 4-verso
    - Nachahmung wird strafrechtlich verfolgt. Alleiniges Urheberrecht bei Luftverkehr Strahle, Schorndorf (Wurtt,), 5
    - Verso: Nachahmung wird strafrechtlich verfolgt. Alleiniges Urheberrecht bei Luftverkehr Strahle, Schorndorf (Wurtt,), 5-verso
    - Nachahmung wird strafrechtlich verfolgt. Alleiniges Urheberrecht bei Luftverkehr Strahle, Schorndorf (Wurtt,), 6
    - Verso: Nachahmung wird strafrechtlich verfolgt. Alleiniges Urheberrecht bei Luftverkehr Strahle, Schorndorf (Wurtt,), 6-verso
    - Nachahmung wird strafrechtlich verfolgt. Alleiniges Urheberrecht bei Luftverkehr Strahle, Schorndorf (Wurtt,), 7
    - Verso: Nachahmung wird strafrechtlich verfolgt. Alleiniges Urheberrecht bei Luftverkehr Strahle, Schorndorf (Wurtt,), 7-verso
    - Nachahmung wird strafrechtlich verfolgt. Alleiniges Urheberrecht bei Luftverkehr Strahle, Schorndorf (Wurtt,), 8
    - Verso: Nachahmung wird strafrechtlich verfolgt. Alleiniges Urheberrecht bei Luftverkehr Strahle, Schorndorf (Wurtt,), 8-verso
    - Aero Lloyd Luftbild; G.m.b.H., 9
    - Verso: Aero Lloyd Luftbild; G.m.b.H., 9-verso
    - Flygfoto, Oscar Bladh, Reproduktion utan medg. beivras, Benno Beckemans, Fotografiska Magasin, 10
    - Verso: Flygfoto, Oscar Bladh, Reproduktion utan medg. beivras, Benno Beckemans, Fotografiska Magasin, 10-verso
    - Flygfoto, Oscar Bladh, Reproduktion utan medg. beivras, Benno Beckemans, Fotografiska Magasin, 11
    - Verso: Flygfoto, Oscar Bladh, Reproduktion utan medg. beivras, Benno Beckemans, Fotografiska Magasin, 11-verso
    - Flygfoto, Oscar Bladh, Reproduktion utan medg. beivras, Benno Beckemans, Fotografiska Magasin, 12
    - Verso: Flygfoto, Oscar Bladh, Reproduktion utan medg. beivras, Benno Beckemans, Fotografiska Magasin, 12-verso
    - Flygfoto, Oscar Bladh, Reproduktion utan medg. beivras, Benno Beckemans, Fotografiska Magasin, 13
    - Verso: Flygfoto, Oscar Bladh, Reproduktion utan medg. beivras, Benno Beckemans, Fotografiska Magasin, 13-verso
    - Koninklijke Luchtvaart Mij., Fototechinische Dienst Vliegveld Waalhaven-Rotterdam, Auteurshecht Voorbehouden, 14
    - Verso: Koninklijke Luchtvaart Mij., Fototechinische Dienst Vliegveld Waalhaven-Rotterdam, Auteurshecht Voorbehouden, 14-verso
    - Coal mine "Wilhelmina" near Heerlen (Limburg); Koninklijke Luchtvaart Mij., Fototechinische Dienst Vliegveld Waalhaven-Rotterdam, Auteurshecht Voorbehouden, 15
    - Verso: Coal mine "Wilhelmina" near Heerlen (Limburg); Koninklijke Luchtvaart Mij., Fototechinische Dienst Vliegveld Waalhaven-Rotterdam, Auteurshecht Voorbehouden, 15-verso
    - Buccurestu di Aeroplan; Pentru Monumentul Aviatorilor; "Le Pare Carol", 16
    - Verso: Buccurestu di Aeroplan; Pentru Monumentul Aviatorilor; "Le Pare Carol", 16-verso
    - Chateau de Belvedere, 17
    - Verso: Chateau de Belvedere, 17-verso
    - Roumanie; Monastere de Caldarusani, 18
    - Verso: Roumanie; Monastere de Caldarusani, 18-verso
    - Arriving over Paris in a storm. Notre Dame below, 19
    - Verso: Arriving over Paris in a storm. Notre Dame below, 19-verso
    - Constantinoples, 20
    - Verso: Constantinoples, 20-verso
    - No matter how you tilt your plane the Leaning Tower still leans as much as ever, 21
    - Verso: No matter how you tilt your plane the Leaning Tower still leans as much as ever, 21-verso
    - C.A.F. Compiegne (Eglise Saint Jacques); Copyright, compagnie Arienne Francaise, 18, Rue de Nanterre, Suresnes, 22
    - Verso: C.A.F. Compiegne (Eglise Saint Jacques); Copyright, compagnie Arienne Francaise, 18, Rue de Nanterre, Suresnes, 22-verso
    - Copyright, Comagnie Arienne Francaise, 39, Rue Cambon, Paris, 23
    - Verso: Copyright, Comagnie Arienne Francaise, 39, Rue Cambon, Paris, 23-verso
    - C.A.F. Pont-à-Mousson (Abbaye de Mousson); Licence de la navigation aerienne 001, autorisation special du 14 Avril 1922 Copyright, compagnie Arienne Francaise, 18, Rue de Nanterre, Suresnes, 24
    - Verso: C.A.F. Pont-à-Mousson (Abbaye de Mousson); Licence de la navigation aerienne 001, autorisation special du 14 Avril 1922 Copyright, compagnie Arienne Francaise, 18, Rue de Nanterre, Suresnes, 24-verso
    - [European Skyways aerial view of city from plane], 25
    - [European Skyways aerial view of plains], 26
    - [Aerial view of European port: European Skyways], 27
    - [View of a European port from a European Skyways plane], 28
    - [Ship port in Europe, taken from a European Skyways plane], 29
    - [European building taken from a European Skyways plane], 30
    - [Aerial view of a European building taken from a European Skyways plane], 31
    - [View of Italy from a European Skyways plane], 32
    - [Aerial view of a large European city from a European Skyways plane], 33
    - [European cathedral (?) taken from a European Skyways plane], 34
    - [View of a shore in Europe from a European Skyways plane], 35
  - Subject files: European Skyways, 1926; 15 (Box 1542)
    - Shulluks at Malakal; A. J. C. [A. J. Cobham], 1
    - Verso: Shulluks at Malakal; A. J. C. [A. J. Cobham], 1-verso
    - War dance by Shulluks at Malakal; A. J. C. [A. J. Cobham], 2
    - Verso: War dance by Shulluks at Malakal; A. J. C. [A. J. Cobham], 2-verso
    - Karnak; Nile in background; A. J. Cobham, 3
    - Verso: Karnak; Nile in background; A. J. Cobham, 3-verso
    - Ruins at Karnak; A. J. Cobham, 4
    - Verso: Ruins at Karnak; A. J. Cobham, 4-verso
    - Polderboezem bij Kinderdijk; Verso: Holland, 5
    - Caption: Polderboezem bij Kinderdijk; Verso: Holland, 5-verso
    - "Jack" and "Erik"; Air Service Engineering Division, Official Photograph, 6
    - Verso: "Jack" and "Erik"; Air Service Engineering Division, Official Photograph, 6-verso
    - Sailing ships locked in the ice pack in the Gulf of Finland; Please return to Lowell Thomas, Pawling, 7
    - Verso: Sailing ships locked in the ice pack in the Gulf of Finland; Please return to Lowell Thomas, Pawling, 7-verso
    - An aerial view of the famous Castle of Lichtenstein on a crag in the Tyrol. The plane is an all-metal, single-engined Junkers; L.T. on his 25,000 flight over Europe, Asia and Africa, 8
    - Verso: An aerial view of the famous Castle of Lichtenstein on a crag in the Tyrol. The plane is an all-metal, single-engined Junkers; L.T. on his 25,000 flight over Europe, Asia and Africa, 8-verso
    - [signed by Titayna], 9
    - [signed by Titayna], 10
    - [signed by Titayna], 11
    - Curtis & Miller Commercial Photographers, Seattle, Washington, 12
    - Verso: Curtis & Miller Commercial Photographers, Seattle, Washington, 12-verso
    - Shades of Hanibal [sic] and Napoleon! What comments do they make as they gaze in wonder at this modern way of conquering the Alps?, 13
    - Verso: Shades of Hanibal [sic] and Napoleon! What comments do they make as they gaze in wonder at this modern way of conquering the Alps?, 13-verso
    - Crossing the Black Steppes on the flight from Berlin to Moscow, 14
    - Verso: Crossing the Black Steppes on the flight from Berlin to Moscow, 14-verso
    - Dirty country in the Balkans - the witches cauldron of Europe, 15
    - Verso: Dirty country in the Balkans - the witches cauldron of Europe, 15-verso
    - Swiss; Schweiz. Luftverkehrs-A.-G., Ad Astra-Aero, Aviation Suisse S.A., Zurich, Fliegeraufnahme - Photo prise d'avion, 16
    - Verso: Swiss; Schweiz. Luftverkehrs-A.-G., Ad Astra-Aero, Aviation Suisse S.A., Zurich, Fliegeraufnahme - Photo prise d'avion, 16-verso
    - Swiss; Schweiz. Luftverkehrs-A.-G., Ad Astra-Aero, Aviation Suisse S.A., Zurich, Fliegeraufnahme - Photo prise d'avion, 17
    - Verso: Swiss; Schweiz. Luftverkehrs-A.-G., Ad Astra-Aero, Aviation Suisse S.A., Zurich, Fliegeraufnahme - Photo prise d'avion, 17-verso
    - Schweiz. Luftverkehrs-A.-G., Ad Astra-Aero, Aviation Suisse S.A., Zurich, Fliegeraufnahme - Photo prise d'avion, 18
    - Verso: Schweiz. Luftverkehrs-A.-G., Ad Astra-Aero, Aviation Suisse S.A., Zurich, Fliegeraufnahme - Photo prise d'avion, 18-verso
    - Stapelwolken op 3000 Meter; Koninklijke Luchtvaart Mij., Fototechinische Dienst Vliegveld Waalhaven-Rotterdam, Auteurshecht Voorbehouden, 19
    - Verso: Stapelwolken op 3000 Meter; Koninklijke Luchtvaart Mij., Fototechinische Dienst Vliegveld Waalhaven-Rotterdam, Auteurshecht Voorbehouden, 19-verso
    - [Egyptian pyramids taken from a European Skyways plane], 20
    - [European Skyways plane, K-SALO, over a boat], [2 copies], 21
    - [Ship sailing through icebergs], 22
    - [Aerial view of snowy mountains taken from a European Skyways plane], 23
    - [Mountains topped with clouds, taken from a European Skyways plane], 24
    - [Cloudy mountain view taken from a European Skyways plane], 25
    - [Clouds], 26
    - [Clouds], 27
    - [Top of a volcano (?)], 28
    - [Aerial view of an active volcano], 29
    - [Aerial view of a river and clouds taken from a European Skyways plane], 30
  - Subject files: European Skyways, 1926; 16 (Box 1542)
    - Above cloud land, along the skyways of Europe, 1
    - Verso: Above cloud land, along the skyways of Europe, 1-verso
    - Over Miller Field, 2
    - Verso: Over Miller Field, 2-verso
    - Austria, 3
    - Verso: Austria, 3-verso
    - Attention! Ne pas omettre notre signature: Studio G. L. Manuel Frere, 37, rue Dumont - Urville, Paris, 4
    - Verso: Attention! Ne pas omettre notre signature: Studio G. L. Manuel Frere, 37, rue Dumont - Urville, Paris, 4-verso
    - chap. 31- no. 3. All Europe, including the Prince of Wales, takes to the air. His fellow voyager is Admiral Mark Kerr, 5
    - Verso: chap. 31- no. 3. All Europe, including the Prince of Wales, takes to the air. His fellow voyager is Admiral Mark Kerr, 5-verso
    - [European Skyways plane flying over Europe], [2 copies], 6
    - [Plane from European Skyways flying over fields in Europe], 7
    - [European Skyways plane flyine over European landscape], 8
    - [Shot of a European Skyways plane], 9
    - [European Skyways plane flying over Europe], [2 copies], 10
    - [Plane from European Skyways flying over mountains in Europe ], 11
    - [European Skyways plane soaring through the clouds], [2 copies], 12
    - [European Skyways plane flying through the clouds], 13
    - [European Skyways plane in the clouds], 14
    - [European Skyways plane flying over European mountains], 15
    - [European Skyways plane flying over a European city], 16
    - [Two piolets in a plane for European Skyways], 17
    - [Line of men standing outside a plane], 18
    - [Plane on the runway], 19
    - [FOKKER plane taking off from the runway], 20
    - [FOKKER plane on the runway], 21
    - [European Skyways plane, D741], 22
    - [European Skyways plane, D766], 23
    - [Two planes in the show], 24
    - [Piolet for European Skyways], 25
  - Subject files: Robert Beverley Evans, circa 1970s; 17 (Box 1542)
    - Left, Wm. Latady, scientist, mountaineer, Antarctic explorer; [Lowell Thomas]; Robt. B. Evans, financier; Dr. P. S. Gill, cosmic ray scientist, 1
    - Verso: Left, Wm. Latady, scientist, mountaineer, Antarctic explorer; [Lowell Thomas]; Robt. B. Evans, financier; Dr. P. S. Gill, cosmic ray scientist, 1-verso
    - [Wm. Latady scientist, mountaineer, Antarctic explorer; Lowell Thomas; Robert Evans, financer; Dr. P.S. Gill, cosmic ray scientist ], 2
  - Subject files: Examples of popularity, circa 1930s - 1970s; 18 (Box 1542)
    - Methodist Church, Princeton, N.J., 1
    - Verso: Methodist Church, Princeton, N.J., 1-verso
    - Methodist Ch., Princeton, 2
    - Verso: Methodist Ch., Princeton, 2-verso
    - [Girl opening the door to the Methodist Church, Princeton, N.J.], 3
    - [Bathroom used by Lowell Thomas on June 1, 1934], [8 copies], 4
    - [Shenandoah Valley Motel; "Lowell Thomas used this shower June 1, 1934], 5
    - Babies, Streets, Ski trails, schools, islands and mountains are named for L.T., 6
    - Verso: Babies, Streets, Ski trails, schools, islands and mountains are named for L.T., 6-verso
    - Note: I believe this is [?], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas and others standing under the sign for Lowell Street], [2 copies], 8
    - Regard from the Beck's Lowell Thomas Inn, Ansonia, Ohio [?], 9
    - Verso: Regard from the Beck's Lowell Thomas Inn, Ansonia, Ohio [?], 9-verso
    - Regard from the Beck's Lowell Thomas Inn, Ansonia, Ohio [?], 10
    - Verso: Regard from the Beck's Lowell Thomas Inn, Ansonia, Ohio [?], 10-verso
    - [Sign for Pepsi-Cola in Greenville, "Birthplace of Loweel Thomas at Woodington"], 11
    - Victor, 12
    - Verso: Victor, 12-verso
    - In Victor - The Cripple Creek District which in L.T.'s day called itself "The World's Greatest Gold Camp", 13
    - Verso: In Victor - The Cripple Creek District which in L.T.'s day called itself "The World's Greatest Gold Camp", 13-verso
    - [Building with a sign that says, "Lowell Thomas 3:45"], 14
  Box 1543
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club, 1930s; 1 (Box 1543)
    - Soviet fliers, 1937, at Waldorf-Astoria, 1
    - Verso: Soviet fliers, 1937, at Waldorf-Astoria, 1-verso
    - Three famous travelers gathered around the huge globe at The Explorers Club, in New York City. On the right is Russell Owen of the 1932 Byrd Antarctic expedition. In the center is Dean Smith, ace of airmail pilots, and polar flyer. On the left, the Sunoco News Voice of the Air [Lowell Thomas], 2
    - Verso: Three famous travelers gathered around the huge globe at The Explorers Club, in New York City. On the right is Russell Owen of the 1932 Byrd Antarctic expedition. In the center is Dean Smith, ace of airmail pilots, and polar flyer. On the left, the Sunoco News Voice of the Air [Lowell Thomas], 2-verso
    - L. T. (right) and Carveth Wells, left, at The Explorers Club in New York, planning an expedition, 3
    - Verso: L. T. (right) and Carveth Wells, left, at The Explorers Club in New York, planning an expedition, 3-verso
    - Carveth Wells + L.T., 4
    - Verso: Carveth Wells + L.T., 4-verso
    - Carveth Wells (second from left), Clanfergus (in kilt) [Lowell Thomas third from left], 5
    - Verso: Carveth Wells (second from left), Clanfergus (in kilt) [Lowell Thomas third from left], 5-verso
    - [Explorers Club], 6
    - [Explorers Club], 7
    - [Explorers Club], 8
    - At old Explorers Club Headquarters; Col Roosevelt [Theodore Roosevelt, Jr.] and ? [Lowell Thomas at right], 9
    - Verso: At old Explorers Club Headquarters; Col Roosevelt [Theodore Roosevelt, Jr.] and ? [Lowell Thomas at right], 9-verso
    - LT at Schaefer Square, World's Fair, making imprint of hands and feet in cement. With him are Dr. Roy Chapman Andrews, Major J. Allan Dunn, Sir Hubert Wilkins, Bonney Powell, Matt Henson, Vilhjalmur Stefansson, etc. [photograph signed by Roy Chapman Andrews, Matthew A. Henson, Vilhjalmur Stefansson], 10
    - Verso: LT at Schaefer Square, World's Fair, making imprint of hands and feet in cement. With him are Dr. Roy Chapman Andrews, Major J. Allan Dunn, Sir Hubert Wilkins, Bonney Powell, Matt Henson, Vilhjalmur Stefansson, etc. [photograph signed by Roy Chapman Andrews, Matthew A. Henson, Vilhjalmur Stefansson], 10-verso
    - Caption: Roy Chapman Andrews, Hubert Wilkins, Matthew Henson, Vilhjalmur Stefansson, 11
    - [left to right: unidentified man, Sir Hubert Wilkins, Admiral Richard E. Byrd, Lowell Thomas and Vilhjalmur Stefansson], 12
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club (Ford Exposition banquet for Admiral Richard E. Byrd), 1939; 2 (Box 1543)
    - FORD EXPOSITION BIDS GOODBYE TO ADMIRAL BYRD The Ford Exposition was host at New York's principal farewell banquet to Rear Admiral Richard E. Byrd, about to leave on his third Antarctic Expedition, at the New York World's Fair. The banquet was organized by the Order of Adventures, and more than 200 national and international figures were guests. Left to right at the speakers' table are Phillips Carlin of the National Broadcasting Company; Captain Felix Riesenberg, retired naval officer, author and explorer; Senator Frederic C. Walcott of Connecticut; Frank E. Mason, vice president of the National Broadcasting Company; Mrs. Lenox Lohr; F.L. Black, in charge of the Ford Exposition; Mrs. Roy Chapman Andrews; Admiral Byrd; Lowell Thomas, famed radio commentator; Alice Roosevelt Longworth; Dr. Roy Chapman Andrews, director of the American Museum of Natural History; Mrs. Lowell Thomas; Major Lenox Lohr, president of the National Broadcasting Company; Mrs. Frank Mason; Col. Theodore Roosevelt; Leslie Bain, director of the Order of Adventures., 1
    - Note: FORD EXPOSITION BIDS GOODBYE TO ADMIRAL BYRD The Ford Exposition was host at New York's principal farewell banquet to Rear Admiral Richard E. Byrd, about to leave on his third Antarctic Expedition, at the New York World's Fair. The banquet was organized by the Order of Adventures, and more than 200 national and international figures were guests. Left to right at the speakers' table are Phillips Carlin of the National Broadcasting Company; Captain Felix Riesenberg, retired naval officer, author and explorer; Senator Frederic C. Walcott of Connecticut; Frank E. Mason, vice president of the National Broadcasting Company; Mrs. Lenox Lohr; F.L. Black, in charge of the Ford Exposition; Mrs. Roy Chapman Andrews; Admiral Byrd; Lowell Thomas, famed radio commentator; Alice Roosevelt Longworth; Dr. Roy Chapman Andrews, director of the American Museum of Natural History; Mrs. Lowell Thomas; Major Lenox Lohr, president of the National Broadcasting Company; Mrs. Frank Mason; Col. Theodore Roosevelt; Leslie Bain, director of the Order of Adventures., 2
    - [Dinner at the Ford Exposition], 3
    - Admiral Byrd [left], Roy Chapman Andrews [right] [Lowell Thomas, center], 1939, 4
    - Verso: Admiral Byrd [left], Roy Chapman Andrews [right] [Lowell Thomas, center], 1939, 4-verso
    - [right to left: Roy Chapman Andrews, Lowell Thomas, Richard E. Byrd, Theodore Roosevelt, Jr. (with back to camera)], 5
    - [right to left: Roy Chapman Andrews, Lowell Thomas, Richard E. Byrd, Theodore Roosevelt, Jr. (with back to camera)], 6
    - [right to left: Roy Chapman Andrews, Lowell Thomas, Richard E. Byrd, Theodore Roosevelt, Jr. (with back to camera)], 7
    - From left to right: the late Brigadier General Theodore Roosevelt, Jr., Felix Reisenberg, Admiral Byrd, Lowell Thomas, and Dr. Roy Chapman Andrews, from the World's Fair, 8
    - From left to right: the late Brigadier General Theodore Roosevelt, Jr., Felix Reisenberg, Admiral Byrd, Lowell Thomas, and Dr. Roy Chapman Andrews, from the World's Fair, 9
    - From left to right: the late Brigadier General Theodore Roosevelt, Jr., Felix Reisenberg, Admiral Byrd, Lowell Thomas, and Dr. Roy Chapman Andrews, from the World's Fair, 10
    - From left to right: the late Brigadier General Theodore Roosevelt, Jr., Felix Reisenberg, Admiral Byrd, Lowell Thomas, and Dr. Roy Chapman Andrews, from the World's Fair, 11
    - [Lowell Thomas and three other men talking], 12
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking with me in front of an NBC microphone], 13
    - [Lowell Thomas and others], 14
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club (Ford Exposition banquet for Vilhjalmur Stefansson), 1939; 3 (Box 1543)
    - Note: FORD HONORS STEFANSSON The Ford Motor Company gave a formal dinner in the Executive Suite of the Ford pavilion on August 23 in honor of the great Arctic explorer, scientist and author - Vilhjalmur Stefansson. Fred L. Black, Ford Exposition director, presided, and among the speakers were Sir Hubert Wilkins, Joseph Robinson and Reginald Orcutt. Scores of notables in the field of exploration and science attended. As guests entered the dining room Ford Information girls in fur parkas gave them flowers. Small polar bears were the table favors. In honor of Mr. Stefansson the Ford terrace, visible to the diners through the wall of clear glass, was decorated to represent an Arctic scene. A backdrop, illuminated by blue lights, showed an Eskimo family cooking dinner near an igloo, with open water, a floating iceberg and the aurora borealis in the distance. In the foreground was a set representing the interior of an igloo, containing a polar bear skin, a rifle and other trappings. Adjoining was a loaded dog sled, with a team of live huskies tethered nearby, squatting in artificial snow. In the foreground a man in parka and mukluks cooked his dinner on a primus stove. This photo shows Joseph Robinson, Vilhjalmur Stefansson, Sir Hubert Wilkins and Reginald Orcutt., 1
    - [Formal dinner for the Explorers Club at the Ford Exposition banquet], 2
    - [Formal dinner for the Explorers Club at the Ford Exposition banquet], 3
    - [Guests at the dinner at the Ford Exposition banquet], 4
    - [Guests at the dinner at the Ford Exposition banquet], 5
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club (Ford Exposition banquet for Sir Hubert Wilkins), 1939; 4 (Box 1543)
    - Note: FORD EXPOSITION HONORS SIR HUBERT WILKINS Fifty friends of Sir Hubert Wilkins, famous polar explorer, gathered in the Executive Suite of the Ford Exposition, New York World's Fair, on July 29. The occasion was a formal dinner given for Sir Hubert and Lady Wilkins by the Ford Motor Company. Sir Hubert had just returned from France (he was in Paris the day before it fell) and Britain. Fred L. Black, director of the Ford Exposition, welcomed the guests in behalf of the Ford Motor Company. Besides Sir Hubert speakers were Lowell Thomas and Joseph Robinson. Guests included distinguished members of the Explorers Club and others. In this photo: Sir Hubert Wilkins, Mr. Lowell Thomas, 1
    - [Hubert Wilkins and Lowell Thomas], 2
    - Note: FORD EXPOSITION HONORS SIR HUBERT WILKINS Fifty friends of Sir Hubert Wilkins, famous polar explorer, gathered in the Executive Suite of the Ford Exposition, New York World's Fair, on July 29. The occasion was a formal dinner given for Sir Hubert and Lady Wilkins by the Ford Motor Company. Sir Hubert had just returned from France (he was in Paris the day before it fell) and Britain. Fred L. Black, director of the Ford Exposition, welcomed the guests in behalf of the Ford Motor Company. Besides Sir Hubert speakers were Lowell Thomas and Joseph Robinson. Guests included distinguished members of the Explorers Club and others. In this photo: Sir Hubert Wilkins, Mrs. Lowell Thomas, Lady Wilkins, Lowell Thomas., 3
    - [Hubert Wilkins, Mrs. Lowell Thomas, Lady Wilkins, Lowell Thomas], 4
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club, 1940s; 5 (Box 1543)
    - Photograph by Bradford Washburn; On Mr. Mckinley in 1942, 1
    - Verso: Photograph by Bradford Washburn; On Mr. Mckinley in 1942, 1-verso
    - [Formal banquet for The Explorers Club], 2
  - Subject files: The Explorers Club, 1950s; 6 (Box 1543)
    - [left to right: Edmund Hillary, unidentified man, Lowell Thomas], 1
    - Family in Alaska; LT Jr. Tay, Anne and LT Sr. [Lowell Thomas, Jr., Tay and Anne Thomas, Jr., Lowell Thomas] with Explorers Club flag, 2
    - Verso: Family in Alaska; LT Jr. Tay, Anne and LT Sr. [Lowell Thomas, Jr., Tay and Anne Thomas, Jr., Lowell Thomas] with Explorers Club flag, 2-verso
    - [honoring explorer Peter Freuchen], 3
    - [honoring explorer Peter Freuchen], 4
    - Peter Freuchen, Danish Explorer, 5
    - Verso: Peter Freuchen, Danish Explorer, 5-verso
    - Peter Freuchen, Danish Explorer, 6
    - E. T. Gilliard; Summit of Mt. [?]; Nov. 12, 1957, 7
    - Verso: E. T. Gilliard; Summit of Mt. [?]; Nov. 12, 1957, 7-verso